Hello everybody.  My K Seltos is
ready after sinking.  You all have seen its
delivery video and then the drive
review
and you have shown a lot of love and support to
this entire series.  So
thank you from the bottom of my heart for that.  So the topic on which
I am going to make a video today is also quite
informative and a very interesting topic.   It is
interesting because the
current insurance policy of my car is going to
expire very soon.  Let
me tell you, today is
30th January and I don't know when the video will come,
maybe it will come after a week or whatever and
my policy is expiring the day after tomorrow.
So my current insurance
policy is with New India Insurance
Limited and the insurance work of my car which had sunk is
also
going on with the same company.
So now after two days since my policy is going to be
over, in this video I will tell you about all the
major insurance providers
like our Tata, HDFC, Ago,
then ICICI LBD, ACO,
what premium rates are all these companies
offering.  Plus, what add-ons are they
offering, IDB Value,
I am going to show you everything in this video
and in the end I am going to tell you
with which company I am going to
renew my policy because
this time I have some requirements which
are fixed because last time when I got it done
from New India, it is not like that
I had any special attachment with New India, the
premium amount was the lowest
in it, for Rs. 13000, I had
renewed only its policy but
who knew, who knew how my
car would sink and I would have to take a
claim because I am such a
person who drives very lovingly.
I never thought in my life that
I would ever have to make a claim and not to
mention such a big claim where
your entire car gets submerged.  So I made a lot of
mistakes in that.  I had compromised on
many things for the sake of low premium amount.
For example, there is no such thing as
cashless garages in New India.
That's why the entire work on my car has been done
on rebate basis.  You people used to
comment on me, why did you order a second hand
part?  Since it is happening in the insurance
itself, you could have got a new part installed also.
Hey, how should I apply it?  It's not cashless,
right?  Not cashless.  That's why
I had to pay the entire repair cost
from my own pocket.  Now I will have to
run to the insurance company.  They will
reimburse me.  So if I had gone to install a new part
in it, the
bill would have been more than Rs 10 lakh by now.  So
give Rs 10 lakh from your pocket.  You can imagine
how big a deal it is.  So that is why my main
requirement is that this time the
insurance provider with which I
will renew it must be number one cashless.  This
means that
they must have a cashless tie-up with the nearest Kia service centre to my house.
If it doesn't happen I won't take it.
I
need second zero depreciation.  I need the third consumables which are add ons.
I also need engine protection
in it.  And if you get a return to invoice,
that would be great too.  Return to
invoice.  What basically happens?  If your
vehicle becomes a total loss, you will get the full
invoice amount of the vehicle, which was the ex-showroom price.
Now companies generally provide return to
invoice only for 3 years i.e. only for 3 year
old cars.  So my
car will be 4 years old, I don't think I will get it the day after tomorrow.
If we find it, let's
watch It's a Huge Thing.  But I need zero depth
consumables engine protection and
mostly cashless.  So let's
quickly go to my room.
I open my laptop and
compare the policies and premium amounts of all the companies and
show them to you.  So you can see here that
I have opened the policy site
here.  Just first of all, to compare all the
normal prices of all the companies
here, I have opened the proper website of all the
major companies in all the tabs.
So definitely we will be
able to compare it.  So here on Policy Bazaar,
click on Car Insurance.  Then
I have entered my vehicle number here
and let's view prices.
Now let's see which companies these people are
offering here.  My current policy is
with New India which I do
not want.  So here we go to other insurers
who are offering similar plans.
So here you can see that our
list is coming up.  First of all you
can see that the amount on your ID is Rs 8200.
So we can also expand this from here through the policy market.
So let me change this from 820 to
9 1/2 just to see if
that's happening.  Ok?  I changed the
IDV to 9 1/2 because
the higher the IDV, the better it is.   You
can see the add-ons here, we have
zero dep, consumables, road side
assistance and the engine protection cover which
I needed, I have also
added it here.  And if the invoice price cover which is
RTI is also available then why
not.  So let's do this now, select first
of all.  Then let us see what each
company is offering here.  So
our current insurance of New India
is giving Rs 16,000 and here you
can see that the IDV in it is 93.  So the
IDV that I have input is
not being given by this company and here only four
out of five selected add ons.  So you
can see what add-ons are there here, the
company is not giving the invoice price which is return to invoice.  Then here you
can see that the company of Zo is giving it for Rs 19000
and here the ID of Rs 944000 is
also giving it and the best thing is
that 5 out of five selected advances are also
coming.  Ok?  Then we come
to Tata AIG.  You can see the premium amount of Tata AI
is quite high and
its IDV is fine.  These people are giving 9 rupees for this also
and all the add ons are available here.  You
can also see Zuric Kotak here.  IDV is this, this is some
premium like this.  You can also see your digit.
All the add ons are there.
Its premium is a very high amount.  And you can see LBT.
This also has addons and its
premium amount is also very high.  So,
I have just got a rough idea about
what these people are offering on Policy Bazaar
because at the end of the day,
I am most probably not going to get
my current policy
done through Policy Baa only and I did
not find their experience to be anything special.
So first of all let us come to ICICI LMT.
I will enter my vehicle information here.  WB20 BM 4015.  Then
I also enter the mobile number and email ID here.
After entering all the details,
I clicked on Get Code and let me show you in
a second which add-
ons are being offered here.  And finally the premium
amount since your car policy has
expired.  Where has it expired brother?  Today is the
30th of January and my first of February is
expiring.  So what
nonsense is this?  Anyway, here's
one, this is a basic one for 13,000 something, this is
zero depth and this is the smart cover.  You
can see the premium amount here, these
people are saying it is Rs 23,000.  So
in this zero depth normal, you will get
road side assistance.  Then Zero Dep
Consumable Car Damage, all these things go into add
and remove covers.
What other things can be added to this?  So it would be
great if the engine protection is added to it.
Zero depth is added here.  One second,
this is something different.  So you can see here that
we can also add engine protect here.
So we have added this here.
And what is Garage Cash?  Recommended for
people who use the card daily to come to the
workplace.  I don't know what this is.  Then I do
n't need that product.  And
we also add return to invoice.  Let's
see what's coming.
So these people will give return to invoice.  I didn't
expect it.  So
after doing all this, submit 26,000 something plus GST
and see, this is coming out like this,
our total is 27 plus GST.
What are these people offering as discount
?  NCB discount these people are
giving 7800 something something.  But I will not
get this because there is
already a claim pending in my existing policy.  My car is
submerged.  So its claims previous
NCB is 35%.  This will not happen.  This will be
our 0%.  So let's try this.   Let's make
this zero.  Then the actual price will be
known.  How much is it after removing the discount?
So this will be our final net price.
After doing this,
you can see your ₹31,900 + 18% GST of LBR in ICICI LBD here, the
price which you have got, in this your ID is
coming out to be ₹9,8,000.
Ok?  We have taken the price.  Now let us
go to Bajaj Alliance and see
what price they are quoting on it.   The
vehicle number is also entered in this.  Then
I quickly enter the remaining name and number also.  I found
Bajaj Ali very strange.
I have filled in all the details.
Then I have also clicked on Get OTP.  It's been
over 2 minutes.
It is still going around.  I don't know
what the scene is.  Let's let it roam.  Now let us come
to Tata AIG.  Let us also take a
look at what these people are offering.
Let's hit Tata AIG with this.  The vehicle
number has been given and the
details of the vehicle are coming today.   It
was a vehicle of February 2022 and it is expiring on 1st February
2026.  So let's
enter the mobile number here also.
After entering the mobile number, your quote is getting
ready.  Let's see what these
people are offering.  So some such coat
is available here.  Hey brother, please check the ID also.
What kind of ID is this, brother?  499
Seriously, the
IDV will have to be increased.  We do the maximum that we can.
So the maximum these
people are giving is 95 and these people with LBD are
giving 98.  So let's maximize this
and after updating the current
applicable NCB is 0%, absolutely correct.  These are
some of my three plans.  Standard Zero
Dep and Zero Dep Pro.  So let us
compare it once and see
what is there in it.  Let's view all the benefits and
compare these three which are our standard,
our third party is coming.  Then
accidental damage cover is coming.  Meaning it is
coming to everyone.  Let us see what is not there in it.
Standard does
not have zero depreciation.  Zero depreciation
is on Apna Depth and Depth Pro Pay.  Engine
Secure is your Dep Pro Pay.  So I definitely need the engine to be
secure.  So
both of these got cancelled anyway.  If you have to take it, then
take this only.  Consumables are also only
in Pro.  So this also became clear.
Rest of the road side assistance is available in both.  These are
all things.  So after looking at everything, if I want to
buy Tata AG then I have to go for Dep Pro only.
Because my requirements are not being fulfilled only in Depp.
You can also see the price of all three to see
what is there and what is not there.  So let's go to Depp Pro.
So these people are not giving return to invoice on Dep Pro.
Ok?  Now it was
expected.  I did not even expect
that these people would give it, but whatever plan we have,
it is right.  So here you
can see the complete price 23000 which is
inclusive of GST.  So in my opinion this is
a good price.  Let's shortlist this for now.
Bajaj, look, this
Bajaj sign is not even in.  You have been redirected
to the login page.  So let's cross Bajaj.
If there is so much trouble just in taking the case to court, then imagine if one
day you have to file a claim, the situation will become
worse.  We will not be able to reach them.
So Bajaj is cancelled.  Just close the tab.  Let's go to
one because many people
nowadays prefer even one.  So let's
see what scene is going on there.  In this
I have already entered all my details.
This is the car number.  The No
Claim Bonus is 0% of its value.  Have you made a
claim in your current policy?  Yes.  And this is my pin
code.  Then there is also the mobile number below.
Obviously I cannot show this.
Go to View Prices and see
this.  Unfortunately, we are unable to
cover your vehicle at this time.  What is this brother?
This is a different thing for them.  Let's go again.   They
kill the price of the car.  Dude, I do
n't understand their sites.  Suddenly
these people get logged out again and again or the
server is down.  I don't know what it is.
So, on those sites where
such hiccups occur right at the time of insurance renewal, the
confidence on them automatically reduces as to
what these people will do at the time of taking the claim.  So okay, let's put everything in again.
After entering, let us see
what prices these people are quoting.
So the current ID is not just this,
brother, make it at least 9:30.  Let's do it at 9:30.
9.49 is good.
And here let us see what kind of price these people are
giving.  So what is this?
Comprehensive plan and this zero
depreciation plan and this is third
party only.  Now I want zero depreciation.
What is written here?  This plan
covers the loss and damage to your car due to
accidents.
OK this covers the full cost of replacement.  So
obviously I need zero depth only.   Let's do
this here.  Then let's go to the
explore plan.  So this price also
seems right to me at the moment.  Now
what's in it?  What?   There
are two plans in Zero Dip also.  One is the Safe
Driver Plan.  This plan is for careful
drivers like you who do not claim.  Ok?
It offers zero depreciation coverage at a
lower price.  And this is All Garage.  All the
benefits of the Zero Depreciation Plan and
cashless repairs at any garage of your choice.
What a misleading.  You see for yourself.  People will
generally click on it without seeing anything else.
But the real cash is here.  Cashless
repairs are offering only this plan.
You will not get cashless in this.
And look at this What Happens If I
Claim?  If you make a claim in this,
₹5,000 will be deducted from you.  For
example, if you are making a claim, then the
company that makes the bill becomes ₹1,000.
So ₹000 has been deducted from you.  The company
will give only ₹5,000.  You will have to pay the remaining ₹5,000
from your pocket.  So there is no benefit in this.  I
also want all garages
because I want cashless and I also
want all the benefits, so for that brother
tell me what does 500 mean,
last and final is HDFC Ago, let's check this also, till now the one of
Tata
AG seems to me the best, let's see
what HDFC people are offering,
here in HDFC also I have
filled all the details above.  Click on Buy Online
and also take a look at their code once.
Hey friend, I will have to enter the number again.
Here comprehensive cover and third
party
is correct. Here obviously comprehensive cover
is required
and tell us about your previous policy type. Yes this is
comprehensive. Previous policy
status
not expired yet. Did you
claim take a claim in the previous year? Yes I did,
let's code it. Ah
one year own damage and one year third
party cover 17,000 something.  Let's expand the IDB a bit.  Let's
try IDB in this by doing 9 9:30 only.   It was done at
9:30.  Updated it.
And this is what happened.  What are add ons?  Zero
depreciation is required.  Did you buy zero?  Yes.
Hey, why are you asking so much about the past?  What have you
taken, what have you not taken, you give yours,
loss of use of down time protection,
NCB protection, engine and gear box
protection, consumables are needed,
emergency assistance, wide,
come on, these three are definitely needed, let's try this, there is nothing else.
Then what is your total
coming here?  After adding all these add ons it comes to 2859
without taxes, let's see the premium breakup,
just the basic premium is this, then
zero dep, then engine gear box protection
consumables, this is this, then after taking third party and adding
all this, after adding the entire GST, it will become
33641,
so ICICI LBA is giving its 31
51961,
Tata AIG is giving its 23757,
ACO 50000,
HDFC Ago its 33000,
so if we compare the pricing directly, then
Tata AIG obviously makes the most
sense in this case.  Now I just need to
confirm whether Tata AIG's cashless
garages are available in Kolkata or not.
So let's search this also.  Tata AI
Cashless
Garage List.   Let's
look directly from their side.
Kolkata here for a second.   Done,
enter Kolkata, do K
and see
which is our K service centre here.   The
list you are seeing here is of
all
our after market people, this is
Landmark Premium Car Services, this is our
proper Kia service centre which is
near my house, so this is coming in it, which is
good, this thing of cashless, let us
also check it in the policy market, you
can see Tata IG, in policy bazaar,
these people are showing 54 cashless garages,
so let us check here, let us
check K dealer garages in Kolkata, West Bengal.  You can see that
they are coming and going at Landmark K also.
So it is confirmed that
my Tata IG will be given cashless garage in the nearest K service centre.
Now look at this thing,
when I am looking at it directly from their website,
this is 23,000 and this is
excluding return to invoice because the
option of return to invoice is not available on their direct website.  But
here in the policy market,
these people are also giving return to invoice.  So
if any normal layman sees this, he will feel that it makes
sense to get the policy done from the market only
because there are all the add ons here
and you are getting a little more IDV here also.
But still I am
not going to get this done from Policy Bazaar
because my experience with them has
not been good so far.  Even if the IDB is a little low,
even if invoice protection is not available,
still I would prefer to get it done from Trust, which is their original website.
So Tata
AIG makes its final decision.  So you have seen the
prices of all the companies, I have
compared them and shown them to you and in the end
I have chosen Tata AIG because its
premium amount seemed to be the lowest.
I was getting all the necessary add-ons
in it and the criteria of cashless tie-up was
also getting fulfilled.
That's why I thought let's go with Tata
AI and experience Tata AI for the first time to see how it is.
Pray
that there is no need to taste it.  If there is
no need to make a claim then what could be better than that
and this time the
amount you are seeing of mine is so much, ICICI
30,000 plus this also comes to Rs 23,000.  This happened
because my
claim was settled in my current policy.  If you make a
claim on your current policy, then the
premium amount of your next policy renewal will automatically increase.
So this is my suggestion to you.
Avoid taking insurance claims as much as possible.  Meaning, if your car gets minor
wear and tear, minor scratches appear.
If you can afford it from your own pocket, then do
not make unnecessary insurance claims.  If you
take an insurance claim,
you will have to pay higher premium next year.
Your no claim bonus will also be lost.
Plus it will also affect your resale value.
So this was a detailed and
informative video.  I thought I would show you
where I am getting my car insurance
renewed.  And I think
this would have been a helpful video for you too.
If you own a K car and that too
from Kolkata, if you are watching then definitely this
video would have been helpful for you.   Let me
know in the comments how you liked the video.
Liked the video Like the video.   If you do
n't like it, you can dislike it also.
Write in the comments which other videos you want to see on your Seltos.  I will
make a video for you.  So let's go bye.